<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graham Griffiths</title>
    <description>A new place to hold my blog posts and projects, work in progress
</description>
    <link>http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 20:24:25 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 20:24:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5-4-3-2-1 Cymru Cycle Challenge</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between Friday 23rd May and Tuesday 27th May 2014, I was part of a 180 mile + cycle challenge from Netherlands to Belgium for Luca and St David’s Hospice.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;charities&quot;&gt;Charities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The St David’s Hospice provide and continue to develop a free and comprehensive palliative care service of excellence throughout the unitary of authorities of Newport, Caerphilly, Torfaen and Monmouthshire for people, their families and carers facing a progressive life-threatening illness which is no longer curable. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://stdavidshospicecare.org&quot;&gt;http://stdavidshospicecare.org&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Luca has been set up to provide Luca with the best prosthetic legs available for his future. This courageous 4 year old boy was struck down with Meningococcal Septicaemia in early January 2011 and his life changed forever. This horrendous disease ravaged every part of his body and in hours left him fighting for his life. Luca lost both his legs, which is why we are raising funds to cover the lifetime costs of specialist prosthetics not available on NHS. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://en-gb.facebook.com/ForLuca1&quot;&gt;https://en-gb.facebook.com/ForLuca1&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had not heard of either of the causes prior to discovering the event poster, which was during an evening out with my colleagues in the urban tap house. I emailed myself a photo, and had my place confirmed by the end of the following week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;training&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a casual cyclist since I learned how to ride a bike, but I started to increase the mileage after my place had been confirmed. My training record started in March, and can be seen below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The yellow markers are comments about certain days. The larger block of red marks when the challenge took place, I kept recording the mileage post challenge until I broke the 2000 mile mark. Unsurprisingly, Monday was not a good day for high mileage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14312583409&quot; title=&quot;profile by grahamgriffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2912/14312583409_96a8afdc51_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Training Record&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the training, I was not drinking alcohol - with a few exceptions, such as my friend’s stag party. I also took part in the Big Bike ride for St Davids Hopsice - an 80 mile cycle from Newport to Monmouth, and back - with a few places in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My diet didn’t change much, apart from the fact that I needed to eat three times the amount of food that I usually would. I don’t consider this a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bikes&quot;&gt;Bikes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have a road bike when I started, but I was able to get one through the cycle to work scheme. Both bikes used for training are below, you can probably guess which one I prefer to ride ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14490600042&quot; title=&quot;WP_000058 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3855/14490600042_d017067b6f_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hybrid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14488463931&quot; title=&quot;WP_000058 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2936/14488463931_26e7663e62_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Road bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were instructed to drop our bikes off at CF3 bar and kitchen on Wednesday 21st May, as I have no other means of transport - this was a challenge in itself. Thankfully one of my friends agreed to pick me up after work. It felt strange to leave my bike, but I knew it would be safe in the van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14312661948&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140521_001 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5077/14312661948_e61f435602.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140521_001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;equipment-and-support&quot;&gt;Equipment and support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was carrying a mini pump, bike tools, my phone, spare inner tubes, cO2 canisters, a puncture repair kit, water, food and clothes. This is generally what I carry on every cycle. The organisers also had support vans on the route in case of any emergencies or problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travelling-to-the-challenge&quot;&gt;Travelling to the challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday the 23rd, we had a coach from Cardiff to Bristol airport scheduled to leave at 13:00 - prompt. I had left my packing until the morning, but made it on time. On arrival to the airport, we checked in and went through passport control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305243968&quot; title=&quot;coach by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5565/14305243968_b41760992e_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140523_002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14468740756&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140523_003 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3880/14468740756_1ae2484bfd_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140523_003&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, there was an announcement for me to go back to the check in desks. Apparently they are a bit sensitive to cO2 canisters in your suitcase, before you ask - they’re for quickly inflating tyres post puncture repair. Once the confusion was cleared up, I was allowed back through the passport control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight took roughly the same time as the coach trip, and it wasn’t far from Schipol to The Hague. We had the first night to ourselves, so a few of us decided to grab some food and take a stroll along the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14511912033&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140523_006 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2903/14511912033_20287accaf_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140523_006&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305341007&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140523_007 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3855/14305341007_8ba77f9655_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140523_007&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14490570014&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140523_018 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3855/14490570014_f749e0d59b_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140523_018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305341987&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140523_016 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3892/14305341987_01ebc238a8_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140523_016&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-one---feeling-nervous-and-excited&quot;&gt;Day one - feeling nervous and excited&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day took us from The Hague to Burgh Haamstede, passing through Scheveningen, Massluis Rozenburg, and Goederede.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305311220&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140524_001 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3884/14305311220_daeccb17c9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140524_001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed the coast between Scheveningen down to Hoek van Holland, at which point we followed the canal to Maassluis - where we had a short ferry trip. From here we headed to Brielle, over a stunning dam and into Goedereede.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cycling started around 9am - we had a few issues with getting slightly lost, and people not staying close together. These were resolved by lunch time, when the realisation of how important it is to stay together in a foreign country had kicked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14511958943&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140525_001 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3866/14511958943_0935756520.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140525_001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With strong winds towards the end of the day, and some people having cycled more mileage when finding their bearings - we had a well-deserved buffet in the hotel and some much needed rest after roughly ten hours on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14511952973&quot; title=&quot;day1 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2895/14511952973_2b7b905f4e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;day1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, my Mother and Brother had travelled to Burgh Haamstede to support me, this was a lovely surprise and somewhat overwhelming. This put me in a great mood for day two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-two---lets-do-this&quot;&gt;Day two - let’s do this!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By day two - keeping to the right had become natural, dedicated cycle lanes were adored, and trams were no longer a novelty. With the temperature around 20 degrees Celsius in the morning - we knew it would be a tough day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305237559&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140525_002 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3895/14305237559_b3d328426c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140525_002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling from Burg-Haamstede to Ghent, we went through some stunning woods before reaching the long dam, Neeltje Jans. We had a main foodstop in Veere, and went along the canal to Vlissingen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14490626242&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140525_018 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2926/14490626242_ed27425729.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140525_018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, we took the ferry to Breskens and headed east towards Izendijke, Flanders, Bassevelde and into Lembeke. With more woodland (Kwadfe Bossen) and some tricky sands we headed towards Gent, following the canal from Ostend. We finished the day in the Walrus cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305240568&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140525_027 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2912/14305240568_1b3bc68678.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140525_027&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was also the longest day of the trip, but the beautiful stretches, dams, canals, and scenery made it all worthwhile. My family said their goodbyes at our ferry stop in Breskens, seeing them again helped me to maintain high spirits throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305232119&quot; title=&quot;day2 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5474/14305232119_6403bc8597.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;day2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-three---the-final-stretch&quot;&gt;Day three - the final stretch…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No ferries on day three, we cycled from Ghent to Langemark, through Machelen and Passchendaele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305234249&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140526_001 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3922/14305234249_7ecdcb4aaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140526_001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started off the day by following the river Leie, going through Afsnee, St. Martens-Latem and stopped off at the castle of Ooidonk. From here we cycled to Deinze, back along the Leie canal and stopped in Machelen-aan-de-Leie for some food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading towards Izegem, we followed the Roselare-Leie canal onto Izegem and west towards Passendale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped off at the Memorial museum (Tyne Cot cemetery) and Menin Gate. Both of which were very emotional places. They provided some perspective on what we were doing, and the sacrifices made that allow us to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14488463041&quot; title=&quot;day3 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2918/14488463041_428b2e8c18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;day3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went via Zonnebeke, into Ypres and finished up in Langemark for the celebrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14490583682&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140526_013 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3859/14490583682_9d023fb192.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140526_013&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;celebrating&quot;&gt;Celebrating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial celebrations and the award ceremony took place. We had a fantastic buffet accompanied with one or two drinks, and a late night (or should I say early morning) in a local Belgium bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305185189&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140526_011 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3852/14305185189_4602f0d7f2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140526_011&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305159980&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140526_014 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3895/14305159980_9183b9fab1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140526_014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-to-go-home&quot;&gt;Time to go home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14305186469&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140527_001 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3888/14305186469_21f3102fb4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140527_001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post celebrations on Monday night, I was suffering Tuesday morning. With a long way before getting home, we headed off on the coach to Dover. Followed by a quick ferry ride across the channel, and then back on the coach to Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14511962863&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140527_002 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3902/14511962863_f74e80aa3e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140527_002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived around 18:30, said our goodbyes and headed our separate ways. I was feeling better by this point and cycled home with my suitcase in one hand, and the bike in the other. Probably not the smartest thing I’ve done, but it worked surprisingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No time to sleep yet as I had celebratory diner plans with my housemates, eventually getting to bed after 23:00. The next day, I woke up just before 12 - well rested and moving reasonably easily. Two days after completing the challenge, I was back on the bike and recovery was progressing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall experience was beyond all expectations. There is a saying in Welsh, ‘wrth fy modd’, which roughly translates to ‘in my element’. I find this quite fitting to sum up how I felt throughout the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/14468687676&quot; title=&quot;WP_20140526_015 by Graham Griffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3903/14468687676_0f0d574358.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20140526_015&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My colleague was kind enough to lend me their GoPro for the trip, here is the compiled footage :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l8Bwdcuxq4g&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/l8Bwdcuxq4g/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 11:56:09 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/2014/07/07/5-4-3-2-1-cymru-cycle-challenge</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/2014/07/07/5-4-3-2-1-cymru-cycle-challenge</guid>
        
        <category>cycling</category>
        
        <category>charity</category>
        
        
        <category>chairty</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bath Half Marathon</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 3rd March 2013, I ran Bath half marathon in aid of Leukaemia and Lymphoma Research. I raised £335.00 with an extra £75.00 from gift aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran in memory of my Uncle Arwyn who was diagnosed with Acute Myeloid Leukaemia November 2011, he sadly passed away on the 5th of April 2012.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be a sprinter in athletics at school, along with running a few long distance races. Since then, I hadn’t done any proper running until 2010. This was when I was living in Bath, and training for the half marathon in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I was unable to attend. After this, I took a year off running and concentrated more on my Cycling. In 2012, I decided to start running again and was determined to attend the 2013 Bath Half to make up for the missed event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;training&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial training consisted of a running between one and five miles per day, with a longer run on the weekend. Eventually I was running ten miles every Sunday. Most of this was all thrown away during my year off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second attempt at training consisted of running three to five miles every other day. I increased the distance slowly and did a trial half marathon run two weeks before the main event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;injuries&quot;&gt;Injuries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annoyingly, I suffered from knee problems the second time around. This is quite common, and there are exercises that you can do to reduce knee pain. Either see a physiotherapist or Google it, I did the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-route&quot;&gt;The route&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trained on reasonably flat routes, Bath is not flat. Thankfully, I had trained enough to overcome the elevation on the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the map we were provided for the event.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/9210866990/&quot; title=&quot;bathhalf by grahamgriffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7441/9210866990_5bb7f72310_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bathhalf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-race&quot;&gt;Post-Race&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the race I had a leg massage, and would recommend that you do the same. I was hungry but couldn’t each much. Refuelling consisted of flap jacks, soup and a pint of orange juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I achieved a time of 01:47 which was a personal best. I aim to beat this whilst running the Cardiff half marathon in October 2013. Thanks again to those who sponsored me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 11:56:09 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/2013/07/04/bath-half-marathon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/2013/07/04/bath-half-marathon</guid>
        
        <category>charity</category>
        
        <category>running</category>
        
        
        <category>charity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alzheimer's Bristol Cycle Challenge</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 25th 2011, I completed an eighty five mile cycle in aid of Alzheimer’s and raised a total of £272.00. Thanks again to those who sponsored me.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling has been a personal hobby of mine from a young age. Before training properly for the cycle challenge, I was cycling to the shops, university, town and friends’ houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bike&quot;&gt;The bike&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off with a mountain bike, but switched to a road bike mid-way through the training.&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7410/8994832198_a8dc1c47ef.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;training&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed up to the challenge nine weeks before it was due to start. I didn’t pre-set myself any weekly mileage goals, but I wanted to get close to the eighty five mile distance. Prior to the challenge, the furthest I had cycled was sixty miles. Below is a record of my mileage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/8994055455/&quot; title=&quot;trainingRecord by grahamgriffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7442/8994055455_673a602ff1_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;trainingRecord&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of training, I wasn’t in University but I was employed temporarily for 7 hours a day from August onwards. The second week of training is me cycling to work and back during the week, with a short trip on the Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I would either go for a long cycle before or after work, and sometimes both during the week along with a long cycle on the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t cycle as often in the week leading up to the challenge - this was to avoid any injuries and fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Bristol allowed me to train on the route. Prior to the challenge, I cycled it in sections over the space of a few days. This gave me a massive confidence boost when it came to cycling the route in one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-route&quot;&gt;The route&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route tracked the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.southglos.info/sg/cycling/routes/regional10&quot;&gt;Avon cycleway (regional route 10)&lt;/a&gt; with a slight deviation for lunch and a slightly different route towards the finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the map we were given for the event, apparently its copyright Alzheimer’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/8993883061/&quot; title=&quot;bristolcyclechallengemap by grahamgriffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8134/8993883061_dcbde3d8e0_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bristolcyclechallengemap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the profile we were given for the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/grahamrgriffiths/8993911833/&quot; title=&quot;profile by grahamgriffiths, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3833/8993911833_9655ef60c8_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;profile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two water stops on the route, these included refreshments such as jelly beans, bananas, tracker bars and other goodies. We also stopped for lunch near Saltford, where sandwiches and hot drinks were provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the day it was raining until the last 20 miles or so, when the sunshine was much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;equipment-and-support&quot;&gt;Equipment and support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was carrying a mini pump, bike tools, my phone, spare inner tubes, a puncture repair kit, water, food and clothes. This is generally what I carry on every cycle. The organisers also had a support van circling the route in case of any emergencies or problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-race&quot;&gt;Post-Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a very much needed shower, along with a well-deserved meal at a carvery courtesy of my parents. I also cycled to University for the first day of term on the following Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me just over 4 hours to complete, this excludes time taken for lunch and at the water stops. I was lucky enough not to suffer any bike problems on the day. The distance cycled was around nighty four miles, as I had cycled to the event and home again. There have been times when I regret not making the one hundred mile mark, but there are plenty more opportunities for me to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 11:56:09 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/2013/06/09/alzheimers-bristol-cycle-challenge</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.grahamrgriffiths.com/2013/06/09/alzheimers-bristol-cycle-challenge</guid>
        
        <category>cycling</category>
        
        <category>charity</category>
        
        
        <category>chairty</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
